妮基塔
嗨 我說你這個白癡
Zap, you fucking moron, huh?
我有鑰匙 你就會砸東西
If you'd just wait, I got keys to open it.
砸了它
I zapped it.
喔 砸了它
你媽生你就會砸東西，你這個白癡
"I zapped it. I zapped it." Is that all you were born for, to zap things?
這可是我自己的家
You're a real moron, you know?
真是個白癡
I grew up here.
你一定知道錢藏在哪
Great, then I bet you know where to find the stuff.
不必我們瞎找了 對吧
Then we won't waste a second, huh? Right.
一定要找到
Gotta have it.
要發財了寶貝
You'll have it, my angel.
對 你得先走了
我親自趕過來
Yeah, well, you'd better get a move on, because I'm going down there myself.
我要他們終身後悔作賊
I'm going to make them wish they'd picked another line of work.
找到沒有
You have it?
快了快了 你忍耐一下
It's coming. It's coming. Be patient!
山雞 快呀
Coyotte! Go, moron!
你他媽昏頭了
For Christ's sake!
他媽的
Shit!
到底在哪
Where is it?
嗨 混蛋 把燈關了
What's the matter with you assholes? Turn the lights off.
你們一大幫小痞子
What do you know, a whole gang of little punks.
在我的店幹什麼
What are you looking for besides trouble?
山雞的老爸 是吧 啊
Coyotte's father, huh? Huh?
安托萬
Antoine?
爸 爸爸
Papa?
怎麼會是你
It can't be you.
我們要找點東西
We're desperate.
想殺你的兒子 老爸 啊
Gonna put a hole in your boy, Daddy, huh? Huh?
報警 我宰了你
I'll kill you!
砸啊
Do it, Zap!
有種的都來吧 老子叫瑞可
Is that all? This way! This way! My name's Rico! My name's Rico!
砸 來吧
Zap, yeah!
砸 快點砸 啊
Do it! Do it! Do it, Zap!
別留一樣東西 砸 快點砸
Do it, Zap, huh? Don't miss anything, huh?
我全砸了
Go on zapping everything!
砸呀 瑞可 我全砸了
Everything, Rico! I'm zapping everything!
砸 砸呀
Zap! Zap! Zap!
殺光了
No more?
唉 不要
Shut up.
安靜 通通閉嘴
Shut up, I said!
出來吧
Let's go. Let's go.
把手背到後面
Hands behind your back.
兩腿撐開
Spread your legs. Spread them out!
你 什麼名字
Name, full name.
妮基塔
Nikita.
我警告你小爛貨
A piece of advice, sweetheart.
別演戲了
Drop the act.
別給我玩花樣 我會盯死你的
You might think it's funny, but I'm on to you.
懂嗎
Got it?
懂了
Got it.
要不要歇一下 警長
You might want to take a small break.
沒事 我知道她這一套
She's fine. She's fine. I know her type.
她沒問題 老把戲了
It's all a game.
給我支筆
Can I write it?
哎 這才乖嗎
來 把你的全名寫下來
Good girl. Now, write your full name, first and last, huh?
我叫妮基塔
My name is Nikita!
根據上訴法庭審訊的結果
After careful deliberation we declare the accused guilty...
被告在聖丹尼區
of having in the community of St. Denis...
涉嫌謀殺執行勤務的警官喬治斯·亨利
committed the willful murders of Georges Henri...
格雷高爾·安德森和米歇爾·泰林
Gregoire Anderson and Michel Terlin...
罪名成立
law enforcement agents killed in the line of duty.
被告減刑的申訴缺乏正當的理由
As to the question of extenuating circumstances...
予以駁回
the jury has found none in this matter.
現在本席鄭重宣判，依照刑法304條的加刑法
Consequently, in accordance with article 304 of the criminal code...
特此判處被告無期徒刑
the defendant is hereby sentenced to life imprisonment.
剝奪公民權利30年
There is no question of review for parole for 30 years.
退庭
Court is adjourned.
30年啊
Thirty years.
我宰了你
I'll kill you all!
我要宰了你
放開我 放開 狗娘養的
Let me go, asshole!
放開我
Let me go!
我要宰了你
I'll kill you all!
讓她離開這
Get her out of here.
先生 我求你 你無權這樣做
Mister, please. You have no right.
我應該去坐牢才對
But I'm supposed to go to prison.
我要見我媽媽
We must find Mama.
我們已經通知她了
She's been informed.
難道她不願見我最後一面嗎
But isn't she supposed to be with me?
我現在想要我的媽媽
Please try. I must see Mama.
你們一定搞錯了
Maybe this whole thing is a big mistake.
她會見我的 她會來找我的
She'll find me here. You'll see.
你們一定要等她來
You have to wait till I see Mama!
我要見我的媽媽 媽媽
Mama.
你早
Morning.
你叫什麼名字
Tell me your name, please.
妮基塔
Nikita
很好聽的名字
That's quite a pretty name.
怎麼起的呢
Where does it come from?
從一首歌裡
歌詞都講些什麼
An old song. What are the words to that song?
先生 請問我是不是死了
Mister, just tell me. Is this God's heaven?
啊 還沒有 不過有這個可能
No, but it's a possibility.
根據官方記錄 你的生命終結於星期一清晨6點鐘
Officially you're deceased as of Monday at 6:00.
經法醫驗屍 死因是自殺
The prison doctor confirmed that you committed suicide...
服安眠藥自殺
by taking a massive dose of tranquilizers.
埋葬於阿佛美森公墓第7段第30號
You were buried at the cemetery at Maisons-Alfort, aisle seven, number 30.
爸爸 我爸爸
Titi. That's Titi.
我是政府秘密行動的專員
Let's just say I work for the government...
我們決定給你一個贖罪的機會
and they decided to give you a new chance to make amends.
要做什麼
What's involved?
重生
A rebirth.
你要學會做各種技巧和淑女的儀態
You'll be taught reading, smiling, speaking, walking, even how to fight.
一切都從新開始
You'll be starting all over.
為什麼
為國家服務
But what for? To serve the state.
如果我拒絕呢
And suppose I refuse?
回你的阿佛美森公墓
Aisle seven, number 30.
讓我先睡一下再回答你好嗎
Would you mind if I slept before I give you my answer?
給你一個小時
I'll give you one hour.
去死吧 死吧
Asshole!
怎麼出去
門在前面
How do we get out of here? Right in front.
那些傢伙幹嗎的
政府職員
Who are all these shitheads? Employees.
大家別動 沒事別動
Nobody move! Everything's fine!
誰說沒事 事大了
My ass it is! Nothing's fine!
我說沒有事 大家別動 沒事
It's under control.
快過來 開門  叫他們開門
開不了
Open it up. Nobody leaves.
叫他們開門
Tell them to open the door!
他們不會聽我的
They won't open it.
那我叫你腦袋開花
停手 放下槍
I'll blow your head off! Just put it down.
你鬧夠了吧 快給我
Let go. Stop it now. Let go of me!
都別動
Hold it.
把槍給我
Now put it down.
好了
你們都回到位子上去吧 回去吧
All right, all right. Go back to your desks.
我第一個彈倉是不上彈的
I always leave the first chamber empty.
你應該安分幾天了
That ought to clip your wings for a while.
你想好了沒有
Have you made up your mind?
很好
That's fine.
在這裡簽名
Forms for you to sign.
你看我行嗎
Think I can make it?
你會行的
You can make it.
我們從最基本的開始吧
I'm going to start you with a fairly easy program.
它像打字機的輸入資料鍵盤
這上面是字母和數字
It's like a typewriter keyboard exactly. It's got letters and numbers.
再看這個 這個是鼠標 下面有個小滾輪
That's the mouse. There's a small roller underneath.
移動你的鼠標
彩顯畫面的箭頭就會跟著你移動
When you move it there, it moves the arrow on the screen.
你按鼠標的左鍵就可以畫圖 它還可以選曲
Good. If you press it, you can make images, drawings.
你可以試一試
Try it.
哎 對對對 太快了 太快了
There you go. Easy. Too fast, too fast.
太快了 慢一點 對 慢一點
哎 不行 不行
That's too fast. Wait a minute.
把鼠標移到左上角 然後回來
Now, bring up the arrow back here, back in the corner right over here.
對 你看 回到這裡來
Go on. Bring it back in the corner right here.
很好 你現在按這邊
That's fine. Now, you press here.
很好玩
Very good.
再來
Again.
這些是一般常用的傢伙
These are the firearms we generally use.
我們從最簡單的開始
Let's start with the simplest weapon... Beretta 93R.
9厘米自動手槍 20發彈夾
Nine millimeter, Parabellum, 20-round clip.
你別小看它的威力
Never underrate a fatal weapon.
在我表明射擊位置之前
Before I demonstrate the firing position...
你來熟悉一下這把槍
I want you to be familiar with this beast.
來個10米靶
Mark at ten meters.
你用過這種槍
You shot one before.
沒打過紙靶
Never on paper.
八，九，十
Eight, nine, ten.
好 下一個
Keep it nice and round.
好
Okay.
該你了
我腿有傷
You're up. Let's go. My leg's bothering me.
沒關係 試試你的反應
No problem. We'll just test your reflexes.
很簡單
It's very simple.
好 就位
In position.
我會保持防禦的
I'll maintain a defensive stance...
你來試著攻擊我的頭部
and you will try to hit me in the face.
下一個
Next one up.
坐吧
Sit down there.
我的小天使 看來你不怎麼樣
My dear girl, right now you don't really look like much.
口香糖吐掉
Chewing gum.
不過如果
你肯和我一起努力的話
But if our efforts are repeated in mutual...
上帝幫忙
and if God smiles upon us...
我們可以把你變成一個像樣的女人
we will then be able to make you look like a human being...
不過一個最重要的認識就是
a step, an intermediate one, but necessary...
男人需要的 渴望的是...
before we have what's essential to a man...
女人
a woman.
你愉快嗎
Are you pleased?
你認為什麼是優雅呢
How about giving me your definition of grace?
我可粗得很
It would sound silly.
也許吧 你可以多一些微笑
Maybe so, then at least you should smile more.
當你來不及反應時 你就一直得保持這樣
You've always got that when you can't respond.
微笑不能使你更聰明
It won't make you more intelligent...
但是可使看著你的人更愉快
but it's more enjoyable for those who have to watch.
微笑很簡單 也很脆弱
And if you have it...
有時候會給你帶來扭轉乾坤的效果
perhaps its fragility gives my girl an advantage.
微笑吧
A smile.
自然點
A smile...
從靈魂裡發出的微笑
and soon you'll have its power...
你會領悟它的威力的
as if from your very soul.
來試試假髮吧
Shall we fix up the wig?
學習的如何
It's been going all right?
不如死了算了
I wish it were gone already.
你有幽默感了 小姐
We've acquired a sense of humor. That's very promising.
有沒有認識朋友
我離不開玩鼠標
You friends with anybody? Yeah, I'm in real tight with my mouse.
能找個酒吧去喝一杯嗎
How about a drink at a bar somewhere?
沒到時候
Not just yet.
這鬼地方不放假的嗎
Don't we ever get any rest in this factory?
不放
Never.
假髮不錯
The wig becomes you.
下星期日是我的生日
Next week I'll be 20 years old.
難道不能放我個週末假嗎
What about giving me a pass for just the weekend?
可以派人跟著我
Have me followed?
你好 我正在設計一個程序
How are ya? I got a program to die for.
你來的正好
I'm glad you're here.
給你
For you.
哦 可以打開嗎
May I open it?
一隻白老鼠 放在盒子裡
Had a mouse named Isher and I loved Isher
膽小如鼠的你 嚇的汗毛直豎
Then I found a fellow who had a face like Isher did
伸直！就這樣 伸直 好
Stretch! That's it. Stretch it out. Good.
現在轉身向前
Now back and forward.
左腿邁出
Bring the left leg forward.
兩個月了
她還是只會找麻煩
Yeah, for two months she's been nothing but trouble.
看來你失敗了
You picked up a failure.
她的潛力很好
She has enormous potential.
什麼潛力
What potential?
除了發脾氣咬人以外
Up till now, except for temper tantrums and biting instructors...
你告訴我她還學會什麼了
you tell me what she's capable of.
高手總要長期培養的
The best ones always take more training time.
也許需要好幾年的時間
Six, seven years sometimes.
算了吧
Oh, come on.
給你兩個星期證明她有能力
You've got two weeks for her to show any progress...
否則就只有把她結束掉
or that will be the end of her.
我認不出你是誰
But who are you? I don't know.
等等 你是...對了
Wait. Wait. You are... Yes.
為什麼你擁在我懷中，親愛的？ 你說呢？
Why are you in my arms, my darling? I don't know.
但現在太遲了
But it's too late now.
畢竟，也許它只是一個夢想
After all, maybe it's only a dream.
噢，我的愛
Oh, my love.
你進步不小啊 在亂跳亂蹦
You've made a lot of progress, mainly in dance...
和亂塗亂畫方面
and also in painting.
但在其它的科目
But in all the other subjects...
你是零
nothing, zilch...
零蛋 懂嗎
zero.
好 你等我一下
Wait for me.
生日快樂
For your birthday.
吹呀
Go ahead.
我們有兩周來證明你值得栽培
We have two weeks to prove you're worthy, Nikita.
如果失敗了 我也無法救你
After that, there's nothing more I can do for you.
你會完蛋的
Nothing at all.
你在看我的手
It's my hands you're looking at?
它們曾經很美
They were pretty once...
過去的事了
but that's the past.
你也曾經像我一樣
You were like me before?
和你自己談心吧
Let go and you'll find what pleases.
發掘女人的美和魅力
The pleasure of the feminine.
記住
And remember...
天底下兩件事是沒有極限的
there are only two things without limit.
女人的美
Femininity...
和追求美的
and the means to exploit it.
你不會吧 怎麼 還沒有弄好嗎
I don't believe it. You're not ready yet?
你別太緊張了
You're too uptight, Amande. It's five to.
我最恨的就是遲到
已經五點了
If there is one thing I hate, it is being late.
你說過 等待刺激慾望
You said waiting increases desire.
快穿上
Slip this on.
你真的要遲到了
You're really going to be late.
我還要用一下電腦
I still have work to do on the computer.
不行 已經到時間了
馬上
Enough already. One minute.
你真漂亮
You're very beautiful.
你來一起晚餐嗎
是的
You're dining with me? Yes.
不尋常啊
今天是你的生日 23歲了
What's the occasion? It's your birthday, your 23rd.
難為你了 你還記得
What a good memory.
阿曼德 要加雙筷子
Amande, we have company.
我們到外面飯館吃飯 好嗎
Perhaps you'd join me for dinner...
走吧
out.
我該去嗎
Should I?
還和平常一樣
The usual?
輕鬆點 把包放起來
You know that you can put your purse down.
表演個魔術給你看 注意了
Now look at this. A little magic.
啊 你等一下
Not just yet.
太公爵香檳 78年的
Taittinger, vintage champagne, '78.
請慢用 謝謝
Enjoy it. Thank you.
祝福你
To your future.
我打開了
May I now?
強力子彈 鈦合金加重彈頭
多附一個彈夾
It's loaded. The bullets are titanium and an extra clip in case you need it.
這算什麼禮物
This doesn't make sense.
你後面坐著的三個人
There are three guests at a table behind you.
穿橙色衣服的女人和兩個穿西裝的
A woman in bright orange and two men in formal attire.
一個是保鏢 另一個就是目標
要當場斃命
One is a guard. The other is a VIP. He's your target. Shot him twice.
完事以後就下樓
進男衛生間
When you're done, go downstairs to the men's room.
最後一間有一個能讓女人通過的小窗
In the last booth, there's a small window through which a woman will fit.
你爬出去以後就到內院
You'll be in an inner courtyard.
然後穿過一條小巷
就到大街上
Then there's a long hallway that brings you to the street.
我們的司機就在那等你
只有二分鐘
There will be a driver waiting for about two minutes.
過時不候
No more.
請等我走以後再行動
I'd like you to wait till I'm out of here.
她在那邊
Hey, look down there.
艾迪
Eddy!
讓開
Move over.
盯著
Stay there.
喬斯
Jos?
準備好了
I have it.
嗨 小姐 等等 你不能進去
Hey, miss! Hey! Stop! Come back here!
給我開門
Open it up.
她...這門有點問題
She's... There's a problem at the door.
哎 你幹嘛
Miss...
該死的混蛋 給我把門打開
Damn it, you moron! Just let me in!
鮑伯 它被封死了
Bob, they had it bricked over.
窗子是封死的
The window was bricked over!
當然是封死的
Of course it was bricked.
你這個狗娘養的
你給我住手
You son of a bitch! Stop it!
你這個狗娘養的
好了 你給我住手 妮基塔
You son of a bitch! Stop it, Nikita!
好了 你給我住手 結束了
I hate you! It's over now! It's over.
我恨你
你自由了 你畢業了
I hate you! You get out tomorrow!
You get out tomorrow!
媽的 你應該冷靜一點
Now just calm down. Damn it!
我們必須...
We have to...
你要想活著走出這個中心
就必須通過這個考驗
We have to do this sort of exercise before releasing you from the center.
你今晚的表現很好 妮基塔
You've done well, Nikita.
今晚...
Tonight...
和以後的日子裡
and all these years.
我會想念你的
I will miss you.
我最後一次吻你了
It's the last kiss you'll get from me.
你看她適合執行什麼任務
Just what kind of mission do you have in mind for her?
一級
S1.
野心總是這麼大
You're as ambitious as you ever were.
沒叫你坐
Don't sit down.
現在給你個6月時間調整 要在9月份準備好待命
Six months' setup time. No more. I want her ready by September.
照我的意思你早就被處死了
Let me be very blunt. Had they left it to me, I would have let you die.
你還不如從他們中逃走
You'd better lie low.
不再另行通知 明白沒有
There won't be any warnings. Is that clear?
能拿幾支
最多能拿兩支
How many are mine? Two maximum.
讓諾 給她
Jeannot.
你叫瑪利.革瑞特 從薩爾拉來的
是聖彼德醫院的護士
Marie Clement from Sarlat, a nurse at the Salpetriere.
銀行就在醫院前面
我們每個月會把零錢匯給你
The bank's in front of the hospital, you'll receive a payment each month.
還有護照 駕駛本
還有零用錢 都在這裡
Passport, driver's license, plus some money to start with.
你執行任務的代號是...
For your missions you'll go by the name...
加斯黑了
Josephine.
祝你好運
Good luck to you.
我很害怕
I'm scared.
最可怕的過去了
The worst part's over.
空氣好 光線也足 還有中央空調
Second floor, very bright, central heating...
而且馬上你就可以搬進來
and the best part is it's available now.
很好
Perfect.
小姐 你趕時間
Excuse me. You in a big rush, huh?
沒有 不趕
No, I'm not.
這台收銀機有點問題
I hope not, because I got problems with my register.
好像在鬧情緒
今天早上傳送帶壞了
It only works when it lights, and the belt broke down this morning.
沒事 那就慢慢來吧 沒關係
I have lots of time.
那好吧 你推過來慢慢算
Must be nice. Let's make a pile here. We'll go through it.
通心粉
Ravioli.
噢 再來一個通心粉
Why, more ravioli.
我比較慢 才來兩天
Forgive me. I'm slow, but I've only worked here two days.
噢 還挺複雜的
But it's very complicated.
餅乾一包 襯衫手染的
Crackers. You hand-painted your shirt?
沒價錢 我想這小玩意值不了多少錢
What would you guess? Anyway, it can't be more than ten francs.
十法郎
Ten francs.
你下班要幹嘛
What are you doing after work?
我沒事
Nothing really.
那 一起吃晚飯怎麼樣
Want to have dinner with me?
十個法郎
Ten francs.
還沒裝修好呢
It's not finished.
我真的有點臉紅
You know, I'm a bit embarrassed.
好像應該找個話題說
Usually I'm the one who does the asking.
你都不跟我說
可我不知道說什麼
You've completely thrown me off. I don't know what to say.
我無所謂
Doesn't bother me.
我是挺沒趣的
Yeah, well, it shouldn't bother you.
好吃 好吃
It's good.
我今天早上聽到個笑話
Someone told a joke to me at work this morning.
我講給你聽
Want to hear it?
不？
Nope?
那好 我趁熱吃飯
Yeah, well, I better eat while it's hot.
小姐 你在製造危險
You know this could be dangerous.
有多危險
What's the worst that could happen?
你馬上就知道了
Left overs?
嗨 你說你做早點的 對嗎
You said you'd have breakfast ready.
我燒水了
I put the kettle on.
是 早糊了
Yeah, right. Don't overdo it.
早餐 公主的早餐
The princess is served.
好吧 先把它吃了 我要上班了
All yours. Because I should go.
睡得好嗎 我的公主
The princess slept all right?
好
Yeah.
請里昂他來家裡吃飯怎麼樣
So what do you say we invite Leon for dinner?
好啊
Good.
你知道嗎 他最近老想家
The guy's really been missing Britanny the past week.
我來做餡餅
I'll make us crepes.
做餡餅？就憑你？
Make crepes? You?
我打算跟他合夥
We might be partners soon.
做什麼
我們造遊艇
Doing what? We want to design boats.
你會游泳嗎？里昂可是好手
You know how to swim? Leon's a good guy.
別損了 他連女人的身體都不敢碰
Yeah, but he can't find his way out of a paper bag.
你的嘴好毒啊
You're so cruel.
也請你朋友來
You might want to invite your friend. Who's that?
你不是說在服裝店碰到老朋友嗎
一個金髮美女
You told me you met one of your friends in a boutique. A blond...
我想是上周
Last week, I think.
是舊朋友
她可不是我的好朋友
Yeah, but I wouldn't call her such a good friend.
請她來吃飯嘛
來往多了就會成為好朋友
Invite her for dinner and you may become good friends.
就算不成 也可以讓里昂摸摸她的小手
If it doesn't work out, she'll help Leon out of his bag.
咱們是天生的一對
We're a good match.
我們在一起一年半了
We've been together for six months.
從來沒有人找過你
Why don't you ever bring anyone home?
沒有親戚 沒有朋友
No parents, no friends.
沒有人
Nobody.
只愛你一個人
I only love you.
瞧 又來了
Look again
噢 正好救命
Oh, no. Rescued just in time.
喂
Hello
加斯黑了
Josephine.
什麼？
一個鐘頭後準備出發
What? The George V bar in one hour.
誰呀
Who's that?
是醫院 說有事
Hospital. I'm on call.
冰茶
Iced tea
借個火
Do you have a light?
一小時客房服務
Downstairs at the Regina's in an hour.
別動
Don't move.
把腿叉開
Your legs apart.
加斯黑了
Josephine.
對不起
Excuse me.
你穿上
That's for you.
我該幹嘛
What do I do now?
坐下
Sit down.
早安 客房服務部
Good morning. Room service.
馬上送到
We'll be right up.
現在呢
Now what happens?
你回家
You can go home.
完了
That's all?
喂
Hello
瑪利
Marie
我是
我是鮑伯
Yes? It's Bob.
你好嗎
還行 還行吧
How are you? I'm fine. Just fine.
我是要恭喜你
你的第一次任務成功
I just wanted to congratulate you. I'm glad your first job went so well.
謝謝
Thank you.
都安排好了吧
Is everything else going well?
都好了
Yeah, real well.
我訂婚了
I'm engaged.
那太好了
That's nice.
你的路走得很順利
I'm glad everything's working out for you.
我要走了 祝福你以後的任務也順利成功
I have to go now. Good luck on your next assignment.
鮑伯
Bob
什麼事
Yes?
我想請你到我家來吃飯
I'd like you over for dinner at my place.
我一定到
I'd be delighted.
鮑伯
Bob
是鮑伯叔叔
Right? Uncle Bob.
快進 請進吧 她還在準備
Come in. Nice tie. She's still getting ready.
好 我來拿吧
I'll give you a hand. You have your hands full.
您太客氣了 真的 還有鮮花
You shouldn't have. The flowers, I mean.
噢 香檳可是好東西
Champagne suits me fine.
嗨 鮑伯
Bob
能認識你真是太好了
I'm so pleased to get to...
你是我認識瑪利以後
To know you. It's...
家裡來的第一個人
You are the first member of the family I've met.
我家人都是混球
The others are a pain in the butt.
我先去把酒冰上好嗎
I better put it in the fridge while it's still warm.
好吃 真的很好吃
不是吹的 真是不簡單啊
It's delicious, remarkable. It's so fine and light.
噢 別別 千萬別總誇她
否則我日後的日子不好過
Stop with all the compliments. My head's getting way too big.
這頂多是不難吃而已
So one more little one, but that's all.
我真的很久很久沒見過瑪利了
I haven't seen her for a long time, and I just find her...
你看她氣色多好啊
I just find her radiant.
你猜對了
本人有一股深藏含蓄的魅力
I have to give you credit. I have a subterranean charm.
這都是你的功勞
Most aren't able to see it right away.
要相處久了才會如沐春風
You could go ten years without noticing.
瞧你
There.
鮑伯 她從來不說過去
她好像沒有童年一樣
Tell me. You might not believe it, but I know nothing about her childhood.
麥可 你幹什麼
Marco, no.
給我講一些她小時候的事
Tell me about when she was about ten.
麥可 你答應過我的
Marco, you promised.
我答應過不問你 但我問他
I promised I wouldn't ask you, not him.
你看連問都不行了
See? She won't let me ask you a single question.
我逼過你嗎
Do I press you for things?
我是心甘情願的
Never, but I wouldn't mind.
愛是沒有條件的
But I love you just the same.
瞧見了 神秘女郎
Yeah, well. You see? A brick wall.
你還告狀
So I've heard.
瑪利
Marie
她小時候很可愛
She was so beautiful then.
那時候她才8歲
She wore pigtails when she was only eight.
老是跟在她表姐的身旁
And she always hung around with her cousin Caroline.
她梳著條辮子
And only Caroline could braid Marie's pigtail.
跟其他的人不同
No one else.
她在辮子上紮了條緞帶
She always had a ribbon in her hair...
她只肯穿白色的衣服
and she only wore white dresses.
我只會在暑假碰到她
I only saw her in the summer...
整個家族在郊外的別墅度假
when the family would rent a house in the country.
數數所有表妹和鄰居
Counting all the cousins and neighbors...
至少有二十幾個孩子
是一群到處搗蛋的造反精
there were at least 20 kids running around getting into trouble.
瑪利還有個看家本領 學青蛙叫
Marie had a very special talent...
imitating frogs.
她經常偷偷溜到池塘裡
She'd sneak down to the pond whenever she could.
搞得自己滿身是泥 蹲在水邊呱呱的叫
一群小孩笑翻在地
She'd jump in the mud croaking until every kid fell down laughing.
然後她就一身濕的回來
She'd come back, dripping and soaking wet...
每次她都一個德行
and every time she would use the same excuse.
「一不小心而已」
"It was just an accident"...
她總是說
with that small voice she had.
她現在還很淘氣
She hasn't changed much, you know.
她沒告訴你我是幹哪一行的
Has Marie ever told you what I do for a living?
噢 我們家的男人不能發問
I'm not allowed to ask any questions.
我是開旅行社的
I've been working as a travel agent.
沒事就得繞著地球跑
It includes some nice perks here and there.
兩張去威尼斯的
Two tickets for Venice.
給你們的訂婚禮物
It's my engagement present.
真不知道該說什麼才好
那就別說
I don't know what to say. Well, say nothing.
老式遊艇
Gondola
司鼓式引擎 對不對
是木頭制的
Drum-like engine, Isn't it?
Real wood.
他也聽不懂
I'm talking to myself.
看這 看這
Look at me!
好了  到了
Ah, yes
來來來 幫幫忙
Ah, ah, ah
來 當心腳下
Watch your step.
謝謝你
Thank you.
這邊請
This way.
不再坐船了  我都暈了
Oh, no, not more gondola.
我要遊船河 游呀 游呀
More gondola, more gondola.
我是船夫...
Gondolier...
威尼斯的船夫
from Venice!
我想要你
I want you.
我渴了 我也是
I'm thirsty too. Me too.
也餓了 我也是
Hungry too. Me too.
應聲蟲 幫我脫裙子
Copycat. Pull off my skirt.
快點
Right away.
開始 拉
Now come on. Pull!
來拿著
Hold this up for me.
你好 我要點餐 一份帝王沙拉
一個七色拼盤
We'd like one side order of ham San Daniele, one assortment of cheese...
還有兩大瓶水
我要和我的男人作愛 一會兒會汗流雨下的
and two bottles of water because we sweat like pigs when we make love.
發神經
She's crazy.
接電話的他是不是嚇壞了
What did they have to say?
他說他也會汗如雨下的
They should have the same problem at home.
這度假真好
It's good to be here.
你別怕
Don't budge.
喂
Hello
加斯黑了
Josephine.
喂
Hello
加斯黑了
Josephine.
我是
Yeah.
浴室的櫃子裡有一個暗盒
There's a secret compartment in the bathroom cabinet.
好吧 那就換甜圓沙拉好了
All right. Make it a green salad instead, please.
謝謝
Thank you.
帝王沙拉賣完了
There is no more San Daniele.
叫他們經理來
Get me the manager.
我洗個澡
I'm gonna pour a bath.
放鬆一下 送餐的馬上就來了
Just relax and take care of room service.
加斯黑了就位了
Josephine in position.
工具在洗臉盆下面
The first elements are under the sink.
組合完畢
Assembly complete.
打開窗子
Open the window.
你叫我怎麼打開窗戶
自己想辦法
How am I supposed to open the window? You'll work it out.
瑪利
Sweetheart?
幹嘛
What?
你猜我在想什麼
You know what I'm thinking?
不知道
No.
第一次在商店遇見你的時候
Of the moment I first saw you in the store. You were so beautiful.
我還以為老天是很殘酷的呢
I thought, "Life can play such dirty tricks...
這麼美麗的女人怎麼可能共度一生呢
because I'll never have a girl like that to share my life.
跟我這個無名小卒
To be with me.
不可能的
Never."
可是我們現在卻真的在一起了
Now we are both here. Together.
準備好了
Okay
運河邊有一艘遊艇
There's a white boat on the canal...
穿蘭色襯衫
with a driver in a blue shirt.
左邊有兩個人在屋門口等著
To the left, there are two people waiting outside a door.
你要瞄準好
Take aim and be ready.
我們再等待進一步的命令
We're waiting for orders.
瑪利
Marie
什麼
我有話跟你說
Yeah? Can we talk?
說吧 不准進來
Okay, but don't come in.
瑪利
Marie
我不想惹你煩 但是
I don't want to bother you with my questions.
我不知道你以前
I don't know...
發生過什麼事或闖了什麼禍
what you did or what happened that got you to this point...
使你變成現在這個樣子
so wound up.
但是我總想著你 有時總往壞處想
But I think about it once in a while, you know?
And I imagine the worst.
可想到頭了也就算了
The worst would be a relief.
誰呀
送餐的
What is it? Room service.
來了
Coming.
停在這裡好了 不是賣完了嗎
Stop, stop. I thought you were out of ham.
算了 放這吧 謝謝
Never mind. No big deal.
幾個目標
一個 要開兩槍
How many targets? Only one, but two shots.
怎麼識別
還在等情報
How do I single him out? I don't have that information yet.
準備  目標十秒鐘出現
Stand by. Target will be visible in ten seconds.
到底是哪一個
還在等情報
Which one is he? I don't have that information yet.
瑪利
Marie
媽的 哪一個
女的
Which one, damn it? The woman.
穿咖啡色的 女的
The woman in brown.
就是那個女人 快開槍
The woman, damn it!
你在幹什麼 快開槍
What are you doing? The woman!
你怎麼了  為什麼不出聲
What's wrong? Why don't you answer?
說過不准進來的
You promised not to come in.
我知道 可我聽到點動靜
I know, but I heard some noise.
我在門外叫你老半天
Damn it, for half an hour I've been talking from behind the door.
你怎麼不出聲呢
You might answer me.
行了 你一個字也沒有聽進去
You didn't hear a word?
好吧
All right.
路上吃
Here. For the road.
小姐
Miss?
巧克力 謝謝
Chocolate. Thank you.
你想說假期愉快是嗎
Want to know how I spent my vacation, is that it?
我越來越瞭解你們這些虐待狂了
I'm getting to know you and your sadistic ways.
你們是一群瘋子
You're mad.
用我來作工具
Totally sick.
跟著你們玩這些殘忍小遊戲
You just used me to play your cruel little game.
看見你真好
It's so good to see you.
還記得當你教官的時候
我真懷念那段日子
I'm guess I'm nostalgic for the times I had you all to myself.
這次是個大使
還有半年他就要任滿回國了
It's an ambassador. In six months, he returns home.
必須在他回國以前完成
你可以選人手組合班子
You have to get him before he leaves. It's your show. Choose your team.
你有6個月時間 上級要求做得漂亮
You have six months. They want a nice, clean job.
我推薦了你
I thought of you.
甜言蜜語下毒手 你的老招了
You're always combining two things at once.
誰要我想念你
The vagaries of love.
不喜歡我送的花
Not impressed with your new plant?
你瞧瞧這個如何
There we are. That's much better.
從今天開始 我不再是收銀員了
No more Mr. Cashier because after today, I'm finished.
我辭職了
造遊艇？
I quit. You'll make boats?
對 得慶祝一下
You bet I will. Let's celebrate.
那當然
But of course.
誰教你這麼笑的
Who taught you how to smile like that?
是你
You did.
咱們搬家吧
I think we should move.
我想你需要一個大一點的地方
I believe that something more spacious would suit you better.
他跟情婦在9號屋裡
He went into number nine to see one of his mistresses.
一般會呆兩個鐘頭
It'll be about a two-hour wait.
你有火嗎
You have a light?
對不起 耽擱了
See you later.
給 回頭見
Sorry, I got held up.
他叫傑瑞 派駐巴黎7年了
Maximilien Jedreck. Stationed in Paris for seven years.
到處搜集情報
He acquires information from all parties...
都藏在大使館保險箱裡
他打算親自帶回去
keeps it in a safe at the embassy until he can take it home with him.
保守的手法
Classic.
什麼樣的情報
無所不有
What kind of information? All kinds.
政治 高新科技 商業
Governmental, scientific, corporate.
女的是誰
Who's the girl?
瑪瑞 搞在一起兩年了
Anne-Marie something or other. They've dated about two years.
藝術經紀人 是賣油畫的 似乎是清白的
She sells paintings. Apparently, she's clean.
其實我們對大使沒有興趣
In fact, we're not really interested in him.
我們想知道的是那些企業和個人出賣的國家機密
What we really want is to get the companies that are selling him the data.
他的情報就是證據
To get them, we need proof.
證據在大使館的保險箱裡
And all that proof's in the embassy safe, right?
對 鑰匙一直帶在他身上
目標確認就好
Yeah, and the keys are in his pocket. At least we know where to look.
兩國關係很敏感
不能出錯
Right now, relations with the embassy are rather strained, so go easy.
這個比殺人難多了
You can't hurt the ambassador.
只能用巧工夫 不能動武
It should be a finesse job, not a tour de force.
有人在家嗎
Anybody home?
瑪利
Marie
你嚇死我了
You shouldn't scare me like that.
醫院的護士是不是有一身藥味 小姐
How can you work at a hospital and still smell so damn good?
我喜歡用香水
Strong perfume.
你好像連上三個月夜班了
如果我沒記錯
You've worked midnights for three months but you tell me nothing about it.
今天是最後一天
Tonight it's over.
比我所想像的還忙
It's much more work than I thought.
她說你可能會在這
She told me you might be here.
瑪瑞她沒有跟你說嗎
Marie-Helene. Didn't she tell you?
她沒說
No, she didn't.
坐一下就走
I'll just be two minutes.
你看怎麼樣
Well, what do you think of it?
還行
It's okay.
讓我拎到五樓來可得多給點服務費
Carrying it up five stories will make a painting worth twice as much.
你喝點什麼
What can I get you to drink?
威士忌
Some whiskey.
你跟瑪瑞工作多久了
You have worked with Anne-Marie how long?
我老爸的畫廊跟她是鄰居
Every now and then. My father owns a gallery near hers.
在同一條街上？
On the same avenue?
對 只差一個街口
Yeah, but up a block.
差一個街口
Up a block, up a block.
我想起來了 一定是那家
Ah, of course.
謝謝
Many thanks.
是芬蘭畫廊北邊那一家
It's up just past the gallery of Finland.
真去過
Ah, you've been there.
喝光
Drink it.
咕嚕 咕嚕
Glug, glug.
躺下好好睡一覺
Now down on the couch. You're gonna sleep a little.
克裡斯汀 有個清潔女工要上樓
Christian, it's just a cleaning lady on her way up.
好 知道了
Okay, I've got it.
加斯黑了
Josephine
是
Yeah?
大使館有暗語口令
The ambassador uses a password with his guards.
我知道口令
口令已經改了
But we know the password. They changed it this morning.
我們的情報證實
We just got word from surveillance.
行動得取消了 是嗎
等一下 我查查看
So we have to call it off? Hold on. I'll find out.
不變 任務繼續
怎麼繼續
No, the mission is maintained. How do I do that?
等著 我們派個清理工過來
Wait there. We're sending in a cleanup man.
這是我的案子 我已經耗了半年
Look, it's my mission. For six months...
閉嘴 緊急通知
Shut up. Orders are orders.
這個案子改為最高級
明白了沒有
The mission is maintained with maximum priority. Understand?
去你媽的爛清理工
You can shove your stinking cleanup man!
太危險了 我看咱們還是撤吧
It's not safe. Shouldn't we go?
等等 一會跟來的人談談
No, let's talk to the man.
莫裡斯
Maurice?
莫裡斯 誰上來了
Maurice, who's coming up?
我沒事 你給我冷靜
I'm fine. Keep calm.
我沒事
I'm fine!
我去開門
I'll get it.
我是威可多 清理工
Victor, the cleaner.
浴室在哪兒
在那 在那邊
Where's the bathroom? Over there.
把大使也拖進來
Bring me the guy on the couch.
司機呢
後備箱裡
And the chauffeur? In the trunk.
人來了 你得跟他們談呀 笨蛋
Talk to the man. He's right there! You stupid idiot!
活得不耐煩了  想跟他們一樣？
You want to end up dead too?
威可多 現在什麼計劃
Victor, we've got to make a plan.
沒有計劃
No plans.
那是什麼玩意
What is that stuff for, then?
救命的玩意
To save your ass.
混蛋 怎麼他還是活的 怎麼回事
You bastards! I thought you'd killed him.
你簡直是瘋了
快幫我壓住他
You're an absolute maniac! Hold him down!
我幹不了了 拿去
I'm through! Get over here.
拿去吧 拿去
Take this, and this! It's over!
瘋子
先把他解決掉
Shut the fuck up. Finish him off.
大使館你自己也能去 把鑰匙也拿去吧
You can go to the embassy yourself! Here! Take the keys!
先把他解決掉 先把他解決掉
Finish him off! I'll finish him off!
威可多
Victor
我們打電話請示上級行嗎
Maybe I should call them for further instructions.
不 威可多
Victor, no, no, Victor
我執行任務從不半途而廢
I am not about to stop this mission.
不准打電話
There will be no phone calls.
不跟我去執行任務
就跟他們進洗澡缸
We'll finish this mission, or you're going with the others. Is that clear?
跟你一起進去吧
不
Maybe I should come with you. You'd better not.
你在車上等著
只要給我一個小時就夠了 好嗎
Just stay here. I'll be one hour.
你冷靜點 別衝動
And please calm down. Calm down.
就給你一個小時
Fine, but only an hour.
威可多
Victor
怎麼可能這麼快
You can't be done.
得完成任務
I'm finishing this off now.
我已經拍到資料了
We've got what we needed to get.
只要能帶我出去就算完成任務了
If we can drive out, that's all.
快走啊
All right?
我得進去看看
Let's finish the mission.
求求你了 威可多
沒時間了
No, please. Victor, Time's up.
快走吧 別逞強了
Let's go home. Please.
那個傢伙是誰
不知道
And who is this guy? It doesn't matter.
大使先生沒事吧
Ambassador, is there something wrong?
噢 天啊
My God.
快跑
Let's get out!
馬上警戒 搜索
The guards are in place.
沒事 沒事 警報器壞了 媽的
It's nothing. It's a false alarm. Stay calm.
威可多
Victor
鐵門關了 我們出不去了
They've shut the gate. We'll be trapped in here.
我還得回來
We'll be back.
站住
Halt!
繞兩圈再殺回來
小心
Around the block, then right back. They'll kill us!
挪一下
Move over.
轉過來好嗎
Look at me, Marie.
我可憐的寶貝
My poor, dear Marie.
不能再干了
They've worn you out.
這行飯不是你能吃的
太殘忍
This job isn't for you. It's too hard.
你該停手了
It's time to stop it.
我只想跟你在一起
You mean so much to me.
這是我人生意義的全部
And I want to take care of you.
沒有任何事情值得去冒險
Life together is too valuable for us to risk.
你在說什麼
Why are you saying this?
我都知道了
It's the truth.
醫院說沒你這個人
There's no Marie Clement at the hospital.
你的經歷我都清楚了
I know what's going on.
你幹的那些跟蹤
How much you go through.
特務 謀殺
The spying, the surveillance...
這都是證明
the videotapes.
你怎麼沒說過
Why haven't you said anything?
因為我愛你
I only love you.
謝謝你 謝謝 謝謝你
Thank you. Thank you.
你是我唯一的愛人 麥可
My sweet Marco.
我真的感覺到這唯一的愛
The world has given me only this one taste of love.
我會永遠記得你
And I will remember you always.
你 你要離開我
You're leaving tonight?
我們一起逃吧
Maybe you'll let me come too.
我們是不同世界的人
I want you to stay.
我愛你
I love you.
馬蒂歐 我先上去
Mathieu, I'll go first.
有問題再呼你們
I'll call if there's a problem.
怎麼沒帶花
What no flowers this time?
沒有
No
到什麼時候才算完
For how long has she...
她欠你們的債
Hasn't she paid her debt?
她就不能選擇自己的生活嗎
Can't she have her own life anymore?
你毀了她
我救了她
You destroyed her life. I know what I've done.
她當年也謀殺了一個生命
But you should know that she also destroyed a life.
一個警察的生命
A cop's life.
讓人無法忘記
And that's too hard to forget.
那她要殺多少來還債
She killed how many for you?
你不數數人頭
Why does it only count when it suits you?
好了 麥可
Okey, Marco
如果你真的都知道
Maybe you do understand the situation.
好了 你知道我們當初是怎麼救她的
Fine, then. I'll listen. Ask yourself how we save her.
這次還能救嗎
Can't you protect her?
我也想
I'll try...
可是她逼著我們追捕她
but she's forced me to hunt her.
我們一定要找回資料
Because we must have all the embassy documents.
那你可以放過她了 底片在我這
Her troubles are over, then, because I have them with me here.
她留了字條 可是我撕了
She left a note for you with it, but I tore it up.
上面說什麼
What did it say?
我們都會想她
I think we'll miss her.
是
Yeah.